Zhen Wang

🕲: zhenwang9102@gmail.com

: https://zhenwang9102.github.io

RESEARCH **INTERESTS**

My research is centered on harnessing the power of large pre-trained models or foundation models, such as GPT-3/4, to make them more interpretable, controllable, and data-efficient across a range of real-world problems. By infusing LLMs with knowledge -centric principles, I focus on the following key aspects to refine and adapt LLMs effectively:

- Interpretability and Control: Enhancing the interpretability and control of LLMs through coherence boosting, probabilistic reasoning, innovative prompting approaches, and knowledge-driven reasoning, ensuring their alignment with human values and responsiveness to relevant context.
- Transfer and Adaptation: Developing state-of-the-art techniques, such as multitask prompt tuning, to enable efficient knowledge transfer, representation, and fine-tuning of LLMs for diverse tasks and domains.
- Solve real-world problems: Applying my expertise in biomedical network analysis, medical relation prediction, and clinical data analysis to leverage foundation models for real-world applications, by unlocking the vast amount of domain knowledge encoded in models to further improve data efficiency, interpretability, and decision-making.

WORK **EXPERIENCE**

Postdoctoral Scholar

Jointly Hosted by UCSD, MBZUAI and CMU

Mentor: Eric Xing and Zhiting Hu

Independent Course Instructor

Columbus, OH, USA

San Diego, CA, USA 2023-Present

OSU, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Autumn 2022 CSE 5525: Foundations of Speech & Language Processing (Undergrad & Graduate)

Research Intern, MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab

Cambridge, MA, USA

Hosted by Rameswar Panda and Yoon Kim Summer 2022

Topic: Multi-task prompt tuning for efficient adaptation of large language models

Research Intern, Microsoft Research Redmond

Redmond, WA, USA

Summer 2021

Hosted by Nebojsa Jojic

Topic: Coherence boosting and prompt calibration for GPT-3

Research Intern, NEC Labs America

Princeton, NJ, USA

Hosted by Bo Zong Summer 2020

Topic: Learning word embeddings by commonsense knowledge reasoning

Graduate Research Associate

Columbus, OH, USA

OSU, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

2018-2022

Advisor: Huan Sun

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Columbus, OH, USA

OSU, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering Autumn 2017

CSE 2111: Modeling and Problem Solving with Spreadsheets and Databases

EDUCATION The Ohio State University (OSU)

Columbus, OH, USA

PhD, Dept. of Computer Science & Engineering

2022

Advisor: Huan Sun

Thesis: Knowledge-centric NLP: Acquisition, Representation, Transfer, and Reasoning

Université Nice Sophia Antipolis (UNS)

Nice, France 2015

Visiting Student, Polytech Nice Sophia

Individual Study Advisor: Lionel Fillatre and Michel Barlaud

Qingdao, China

China University of Petroleum (UPC)

Qiriguao, Crima

B.Eng. in Electronic Information Engineering Graduated as 1st-Ranked Student in the Major Overall Ranking

PUBLICATIONS
(* equal contribution)

Multitask Prompt Tuning Enables Parameter-Efficient Transfer Learning
 Zhen Wang, Rameswar Panda, Leonid Karlinsky, Rogerio Feris, Huan Sun, Yoon Kim

Proceedings of ICLR 2023 [Paper]

- GPT Is Becoming a Turing Machine: Here Are Some Ways to Program It
 Ana Jojic, Zhen Wang, Nebojsa Jojic
 [arXiv]
- ThinkSum: Probabilistic Reasoning Over Sets Using Large Language Models
 Batu Ozturkler, Nikolay Malkin, Zhen Wang, Nebojsa Jojic
 Under Review [arXiv]
- Frustratingly Simple Entity Tracking with Effective Use of Multi-Task Learning Models

Janvijay Singh, Fan Bai, Zhen Wang Proceedings of EACL 2023 [arXiv]

• Knowledge Transfer between Structured and Unstructured Sources for Complex Question Answering

Lingbo Mo*, Zhen Wang*, Jie Zhao, Huan Sun

NAACL 2022 Structured and Unstructured Knowledge Integration (SUKI) [Paper]

• Learning Interpretable Word Representations by Commonsense Knowledge Reasoning

Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Wei Cheng, Xuchao Zhang, Yanchi Liu, Wenchao Yu, Jingchao Ni, Haifeng Chen, Huan Sun

Under Review

• Coherence Boosting: When Your Pretrained Language Model is Not Paying Enough Attention

Nikolay Malkin, <u>Zhen Wang</u>, Nebojsa Jojic *Proceedings of ACL* 2022 [Paper]

• Bootstrapping a User-Centered Task-Oriented Dialogue System

Shijie Chen, Ziru Chen, Xiang Deng, Ashley Lewis, Lingbo Mo, Samuel Stevens, Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Tianshu Zhang, Yu Su, Huan Sun
1st Proceedings of Alexa Prize TaskBot (Alexa Prize 2021) [Paper]

• Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs

Zhen Wang, Bo Zong, Huan Sun

Proceedings of WSDM 2021 (Acceptance Rate: 18.6%, Long) [Paper]

	Zhen Wang, Jennifer Lee, Simon Lin, Huan Sun Proceedings of ACL 2020 (Acceptance Rate: 22.7%, Long) [Paper]	
	• SurfCon: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data	
	Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon Lin, Huan Sun	
	Proceeding of SIGKDD 2019 (Research Track, Acceptance Rate 14.2%, Oral) [Paper]	
	Graph Embedding on Biomedical Networks: Methods, Applications, and Evaluations	
	Xiang Yue, Zhen Wang, Jingong Huang, Srinivasan Parthasarathy, Soheil Moosavinasab, Yungui Huang, Simon M. Lin, Wen Zhang, Ping Zhang, Huan Sun <i>Bioinformatics</i> , Volume 36, Issue 4, 15 February 2020, Pages 1241–1251 (Impact factor: 5.610) [Paper]	
	• A Comprehensive Study of StaQC for Deep Code Summarization	
	Jayavardhan Reddy Peddamail, Ziyu Yao, Zhen Wang, Huan Sun	
	Proceedings of SIGKDD 2018 (Deep Learning Day, SPOTLIGHT) [Paper]	
	 Hessian Regularized Sparse Coding for Human Action Recognition 	
	Weifeng Liu, Zhen Wang, Dapeng Tao, Jun Yu	
	Proceedings of MMM 2015, Sydney, Australia [Paper]	
HONORS AND AWARDS	Third-Place Honor, Inaugural Alexa Prize TaskBot Challenge	2022
	 Graduate Research Award, CSE, OSU 	2022
	 Graduate Student Research Poster Award (Top 5), CSE, OSU 	2021
	SIGIR Student Travel Grant	2021
	Rising Star in Data Science, CDAC, University of Chicago	2020
	SIGKDD Student Travel Award	2019
	• Excellent Bachelor Degree Thesis Award in Shandong Province, China	2016
	 Excellent Graduate Thesis Award of UPC, China 	2015
	 China Scholarship Council (CSC) Scholarship 	2015
	- A fully supported visiting program in Polytech Nice Sophia, Nice, France	
	National Scholarship, China	2014
	Soong Ching Ling Foundation (SCLF) Scholarship, China	2013
	National Scholarship for Encouragement, China	2012
SERVICE	Area Chair / Senior PC	
	- NLPCC 2023	
	Program Committee:	
	- ACL Rolling Review	
	* 2021 (Oct., Nov.)	
	* 2022 (Jan., April, Sep., Oct., Dec.)	
	* 2023 (Feb.)	
	- NAACL (2021, 2022 SUKI Workshop)	
	- EMNLP (2021, 2022)	
	- ACL (2021, 2023)	

• Rationalizing Medical Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Statistics

- ICML 2023
- NeurIPS 2023
- KDD 2023
- AAAI 2023
- NLPCC (2020, 2021, 2022)
- External Reviewer: KDD (2019, 2020), ACL 2018, ICDM 2018

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

• CSE 5525: Foundations of Speech and Language Processing

- ⊢ OSU, Department of Computer Science & Engineering
 Instructor, Autumn 2022 (~30 undergrad and graduate students)
- Summer School Tutorial: Natural Language Processing in Deep Learning
 - → OSU, Foundations of Data Science and AI Community of Practice Panelist, June 1 - June 3, 2022 (>180 attendees)
- CSE 2111: Modeling and Problem Solving with Spreadsheets and Databases
 - + *OSU*, *Department of Computer Science & Engineering* Teaching Assistant, Autumn 2017
- Panel Discussion: 2001: A Space Odyssey Science Fiction vs Science Fact
 - ⊢ *OSU*, *Department of Astronomy* Panelist, Feb. 2021

INVITED TALKS

- "Towards Efficient and Robust Practice of Large Language Models", Autumn 2022, UCSD & MBZUAI & CMU
- "Towards Efficient and Robust Practice of Large Language Models", Autumn 2022, University of Washington
- "Rationalizing Relation Prediction from Corpus-level Statistics", ACL 2020, July, Online
- "Modeling Context Pair Interaction for Pairwise Tasks on Graphs", WSDM 2021, March, Online
- "SurfCon: Synonym Discovery on Privacy-Aware Clinical Data", KDD 2019, August 6, Anchorage, Alaska, USA

REFERENCES

Available upon request